Good morning. You're watching a special
edition of the program with Ted Rall and
John Kiriakou. It's Sunday, March 1st,
2026.
We are normally here Monday through
Friday, 9:00 a.m. Eastern Time on
YouTube and Rumble, but and streaming
whenever, but obviously with the news
out of the out of Iran in the Middle
East,
John and I decided we needed to pipe in
and say our piece and answer questions
and try to analyze things as best we
could. Thanks so much for joining us,
John.
Hey, good to see you, Ted. Glad to be
back even on a Sunday. And I I want to
say, too, forgive forgive my my video.
I'm in a hotel in Brooklyn. I have only
my phone, so I I apologize for the
quality of my of my picture. It actually
looks pretty good, John.
Oh, good. Good. Good. Okay. And you
sound good, too. It's a strong
>> Good.
That's what I want. I'm going to I'm
going to
make this nicer. Okay, there we go.
Great. All right, so let me go over some
of the Obviously, today's we're only
going to be talking about Iran, nothing
else, even though there's plenty else
going on in the world.
Basically, yesterday the big news being
that Supreme Leader
Ali Khamenei was
who's been leading Iran for nearly 37
years was killed by Israeli airstrike
that was guided by the United States.
That was confirmed by the Iranians.
The CIA apparently told Trump before he
decided to attack Iran that there was a
strong chance that Khamenei would
probably be replaced by someone who was
at least as hardline as he is, maybe
someone from the Revolutionary Guards.
Interim Council's been announced.
Ayatollah senior cleric named Ayatollah
Ali Reza Araki, sorry for the butchering
of the language there, has been
announced. We'll talk about that. The
New York Times is reporting that
basically insiders are saying that the
diplomacy never had a chance due to the
way that the Trump administration was
approaching and talking to the Iranians
and it may have just all been
misdirection all along.
Polls showed that only 21% of Americans
support this war at its very at its
inception. I think that's insane. I've
never heard of anything like it.
Normally 21% is like after you've lost
the war and everyone's turned against it
and even then it doesn't get that bad. I
think more people supported the Vietnam
war in 1973 than than 21%. Um Trump is
hiding somewhere. We don't know where.
No speeches to the nation
and no no public no public statements.
Um
oil futures, not surprisingly, are are
are soaring. We'll see what happens when
the markets open tomorrow, but we'll
know more when the Asian markets open
later today
due to the time difference. There's a
and key members of Congress are pushing
for a war powers resolution.
Notably, Ro Khanna, Thomas Massie want a
public vote. Looks like they're going to
probably going to get one.
And so this is a unique set of
circumstances.
The Strait of Hormuz, Iran claims, has
been closed by them. My favorite quote,
John, was from their social media feed
where they said, you know, we have
blocked the Strait of Hormuz. Let the
orange pig try to unblock it.
Oh my god. Oh my god.
>> [laughter]
>> I didn't see that.
So great. I don't mean to I don't mean
to laugh, but
>> have to laugh cuz war does always have
like some funny moments like Baghdad
Baghdad Bob. Um Baghdad Bob. And and
there's like and and then there was also
this really weird moment yesterday. NBC
News, which used to be a news
organization,
they they were interviewing a top
Iranian official and they said, how can
you justify um hitting these military
the US military bases?
And he's like, but that's the places
that are firing the weapons at us in the
war that you started. I mean literally
there's never there's no more
justifiable military action than that. I
don't know, very strange.
Unbelievable. Well, things are things
are bad Ted, bad all around. The I spoke
to
friends of mine in Kuwait Qatar
and the United Arab Emirates yesterday.
It's funny.
The I talked to a a Qatari
the son of a senior Qatari official
yesterday and he just kind of chuckled
and said, "Well, this is life in the
Middle East. We live in a dangerous
neighborhood."
My my friends in Dubai were
panicked.
The Burj Al Arab, the the giant ultra
lux hotel that's shaped like a sail.
The Iranians fired
or not fired but sent a drone to to blow
up on it. The drone was intercepted and
hit in the air.
But when it exploded, it exploded
against the hotel and set the hotel on
fire. The fire was put out but there's
significant damage. The Iranians
sent drones to attack the Burj Khalifa,
the tallest building in the world.
They hit it with two drones.
Maybe even more importantly though
Manama Airport in Bahrain is unusable.
It has to be closed for a while and
repaired. Kuwait International Airport
in Kuwait has also been hit.
>> John about the Bahraini Airport. There's
reports that the Bahraini local fighting
fighting brigade refused to put out the
fight to fight that fire.
You know, I would actually believe that
because [clears throat]
Bahrain is a majority Shia Muslim
country
just like Iran is Shia Muslim and
Bahrain has a Sunni Muslim royal family,
which can be a problem at times.
Heads are going to roll if that's true.
But I it doesn't surprise me.
So anyway, the the the Iranians,
you know, the Iranians can't win this
thing, of course, but but they can put
up a fight and they can they can, you
know, put some hurt out on
on the Gulf Arab states.
And they could survive, right? I mean,
that's what it looks like for them. Um
yeah, I mean, this is a this is a regime
that's really built for survival. It's
been under siege since 1979.
Um the
you know, they they have as we talked
about yesterday in the other extra
edition that we did yesterday morning,
um John, there was a you know, there's
there's redundant governmental systems
there. Um the they you know, these
decapitation strikes certainly hit hard.
Um the Israelis and the Americans killed
a lot of top officials. But you know,
they have a succession plan. They have
number twos, number threes ready to step
in. They always did. They always knew
something like this could happen.
Um
I mean, [clears throat]
as I don't see how you overthrow this
regime
um
this way unless the Iranian people rise
up and overthrow it, but I don't see how
that happens. Which we're not seeing.
So, I'm seeing
I'm seeing video from Iran. You know, on
CNN they'll show you video from Iran and
say 300 people dancing and waving and
whatever, beeping their horns. But then
you see video of a million people out in
the street self-flagellating
and crying and vowing to fight the West
to the death.
And think of it this way, too.
A peaceful transition of power
from the current regime to some
substitute regime is in US interests.
Chaos and death
is what is in Israel's interests.
And that's what we're more likely to
get. And that's what we're more we're
more likely to get. I think Netanyahu is
hoping for a civil war.
I think that's exactly what the plan is,
yes.
Yeah.
Want to support the show with style? Go
to theprogram.live and check out our
merch. That's theprogram.live
or check out the description below.
Thanks for watching.
>> [music]